# **AGNIVESH CHAUBEY**

# Software Engineer Intern

Phone: +91 8052990883 Email: agniveshvapi@gmail.com Portfolio: https://agnivesh.netlify.app

GitHub: AgniveshChaubey LinkedIn: agniveshchaubey Twitter: agnivesh\_01

## **PROFILE**

Electrical engineering undergraduate with a strong passion for software development and 2 years of experience. **Google Summer of Code** (GSoC) mentee at Postman Org, skilled in React, Express.js, and JavaScript. Actively exploring the exciting world of blockchain with Solidity. Dedicated to continuous growth, open-source contributions, and seeking an internship to propel my professional journey to new heights.

## **EXPERIENCE**

## Google Summer of Code

## Postman (Mar 2023 – Remote)

Working on a CLI tool named 'bowtie' which helps in validating the implementations against predefined tests. The tool validates the implementations against number of tests cases and generates an output which is then used to populate the report UI.

- Created an intuitive website using ReactJS and Express to publish comprehensive reports.
- Added <u>Runtime info</u> to harness' metadata (harness the container inside which validation takes place).
- Enhanced the tool by adding <u>Runtime</u> info and a smart <u>dark mode</u> feature.

# **Content Creation**

## YouTube (2019 - 2021)

- Built a successful <u>YouTube</u> channel with over 500k subscribers.
- Created engaging content for myself and clients.

## Blogs (2022 - Present)

I write technical <u>blogs</u> to share my journey, experience and knowledge with the community.

#### **PROJECTS**

- Bowtie Report App that displays the validation result in an intuitive way.
- Portfolio Website (ReactJS) Showcased personal details, experiences, and projects.
- Budget Tracker app Intuitive app to track and manage expenses.
- <u>Calculator</u> Basic mathematical calculations app built using JavaScript.

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

 Advanced React course by Meta - Upgraded React skills with a focus on state management, performance optimization, and advanced component patterns.

- Google Cloud certification Expanded knowledge in Google Cloud and its services.
- <u>Frontend Development Libraries</u> Developed skills in React, Redux, and Bootstrap for creating dynamic and responsive web applications.

# **SKILLS**

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- (Learning-Python, Solidity)
- React, Bootstrap, Material-UI, Node.js, Express, d3.js
- Git, GitHub, Bash, Figma

## **EDUCATION**

# **B. Tech-Electrical Engineering**

Birla Vishwakarma Mahavidyalaya

Year: 2020-2024

Expected Graduation - July 2024

# **NON - ACADEMICS**

- NCC Cadet
- Sports team leader (Kabaddi)
- Inter-school Volleyball player
- Content creator (500k+ on YT)
- Blogs (https://agnivesh.hashnode.dev)
- Meditation guide (2+ years of experience)

## **STRENGTHS**

- **Problem Solving** Overcoming drawbacks and solving problems innovatively and efficiently.
- **Brainstorming** Creativity helped me excel in formulating exciting ideas that have a significant potential to come true
- Curiosity Constantly seeking to learn and understand new concepts and ideas.

## **Future Goals:**

Aspiring to become a professional software engineer and active open-source contributor, driven by a strong desire to make a lasting impact in the blockchain world.